<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % general-entities SYSTEM "../general.ent">
  %general-entities;
]>

<sect1 id="ch-system-introduction">
  <?dbhtml filename="introduction.html"?>

  <title>介绍</title>

  <para>这一章中，我们进入编制位置开始搭建 LFS 系统。也就是说，我们 chroot 进入到临时的迷你 Linux 系统，做几项最后的准备工作，然后开始安装程序包。</para>

  <para>软件的安装很简单。虽然很多情况下安装指令还可以更加简短通用，我们选择提供每个程序包的完整指令来最小化出错的概率。学习 Linux 系统如何工作的关键就是了解每个程序包的用途，你 (或者系统) 又为什么会需要它。</para>

  <para>我们不推荐做修改。它们可能会使程序运行略快一点，也可能会产生编译困难或者运行问题。如果有程序包在做了修改之后不能编译，试试不带修改能否解决问题。即使程序包做了修改之后能够编译，也存在由于代码和编制工具之间的复杂交互而编译不正确的风险。还要注意 <option>-march</option> 和 <option>-mtune</option> 选项使用本书中没有指定的值未经测试。这可能导致工具链程序包 (Binutils、GCC 和 Glibc) 出问题。The small potential gains
  achieved in using compiler optimizations are often outweighed by the risks.
  First-time builders of LFS are encouraged to build without custom
  optimizations. The subsequent system will still run very fast and be stable
  at the same time.</para>

  <para>The order that packages are installed in this chapter needs to be
  strictly followed to ensure that no program accidentally acquires a path
  referring to <filename class="directory">/tools</filename> hard-wired into
  it.  For the same reason, do not compile separate packages in parallel.
  Compiling in parallel may save time (especially on dual-CPU machines), but it
  could result in a program containing a hard-wired path to <filename
  class="directory">/tools</filename>, which will cause the program to stop
  working when that directory is removed.</para>

  <para>Before the installation instructions, each installation page provides
  information about the package, including a concise description of what it
  contains, approximately how long it will take to build, and how much disk
  space is required during this building process. Following the installation
  instructions, there is a list of programs and libraries (along with brief
  descriptions of these) that the package installs.</para>

  <note><para>The SBU values and required disk space includes
  test suite data for all applicable packages in Chapter 6.</para></note>

</sect1>
