<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % general-entities SYSTEM "../general.ent">
  %general-entities;
]>

<sect1 id="ch-tools-settingenviron">
  <?dbhtml filename="settingenvironment.html"?>

  <title>设置工作环境</title>

  <para>给 <command>bash</command> shell 创建两个新的起始文件来创建一个好的工作环境。作为用户 <systemitem class="username">lfs</systemitem> 登录后运行以下命令来创建新的 <filename>.bash_profile</filename> 文件：</para>

<screen><userinput>cat &gt; ~/.bash_profile &lt;&lt; "EOF"
<literal>exec env -i HOME=$HOME TERM=$TERM PS1='\u:\w\$ ' /bin/bash</literal>
EOF</userinput></screen>

  <para>作为用户 <systemitem class="username">lfs</systemitem> 登录时，初始 shell 通常是一个<emphasis>登录</emphasis> shell，会先读取宿主的 <filename>/etc/profile</filename> 文件 (可能包含一些设置和环境变量) 然后是 <filename>.bash_profile</filename>。<filename>.bash_profile</filename> 文件中的 <command>exec env -i.../bin/bash</command> 这条命令用全空的环境替换运行中的 shell，只保留 <envar>HOME</envar>、<envar>TERM</envar> 和 <envar>PS1</envar> 变量。这样就确保了不会有不想要的或有千载威海的环境变量从宿主系统泄漏到编制环境中。这样就实现了确保环境干净的目标。</para>

  <para>新的 shell 是<emphasis>非登录</emphasis> shell，不读 <filename>/etc/profile</filename> 和 <filename>.bash_profile</filename> 这两个文件，而去读 <filename>.bashrc</filename> 文件。现在创建 <filename>.bashrc</filename> 文件：</para>

<screen><userinput>cat &gt; ~/.bashrc &lt;&lt; "EOF"
<literal>set +h
umask 022
LFS=/mnt/lfs
LC_ALL=POSIX
LFS_TGT=$(uname -m)-lfs-linux-gnu
PATH=/tools/bin:/bin:/usr/bin
export LFS LC_ALL LFS_TGT PATH</literal>
EOF</userinput></screen>

  <para>The <command>set +h</command> command turns off
  <command>bash</command>'s hash function. Hashing is ordinarily a useful
  feature&mdash;<command>bash</command> uses a hash table to remember the
  full path of executable files to avoid searching the <envar>PATH</envar>
  time and again to find the same executable. However, the new tools should
  be used as soon as they are installed. By switching off the hash function,
  the shell will always search the <envar>PATH</envar> when a program is to
  be run. As such, the shell will find the newly compiled tools in
  <filename class="directory">$LFS/tools</filename> as soon as they are
  available without remembering a previous version of the same program in a
  different location.</para>

  <para>Setting the user file-creation mask (umask) to 022 ensures that newly
  created files and directories are only writable by their owner, but are
  readable and executable by anyone (assuming default modes are used by the
  <function>open(2)</function> system call, new files will end up with permission
  mode 644 and directories with mode 755).</para>

  <para>The <envar>LFS</envar> variable should be set to the chosen mount
  point.</para>

  <para>The <envar>LC_ALL</envar> variable controls the localization of certain
  programs, making their messages follow the conventions of a specified country.
  If the host system uses a version of Glibc older than 2.2.4, having
  <envar>LC_ALL</envar> set to something other than <quote>POSIX</quote> or
  <quote>C</quote> (during this chapter) may cause issues if you exit the chroot
  environment and wish to return later. Setting <envar>LC_ALL</envar> to
  <quote>POSIX</quote> or <quote>C</quote> (the two are equivalent) ensures that
  everything will work as expected in the chroot environment.</para>

  <para>The <envar>LFS_TGT</envar> variable sets a non-default, but compatible machine
  description for use when building our cross compiler and linker and when cross
  compiling our temporary toolchain. More information is contained in
  <xref linkend="ch-tools-toolchaintechnotes" role=""/>.</para>

  <para>By putting <filename class="directory">/tools/bin</filename> ahead of the
  standard <envar>PATH</envar>, all the programs installed in <xref
  linkend="chapter-temporary-tools"/> are picked up by the shell immediately after
  their installation. This, combined with turning off hashing, limits the risk
  that old programs are used from the host when the same programs are available in
  the chapter 5 environment.</para>

  <para>Finally, to have the environment fully prepared for building the
  temporary tools, source the just-created user profile:</para>

<screen><userinput>source ~/.bash_profile</userinput></screen>

</sect1>
